<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[SmokinClove's (mainly) CSS Nonsense]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog by SmokinClove. Built with Gatsby]]></description><link>https://smokinclove.github.io/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 04:58:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[TIL#6]]></title><description><![CDATA[1 Oh hey i learned a new word today! highfalutin: pompous or pretentious Source article with the word: http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/china…]]></description><link>https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/18072019/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/18072019/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh hey i learned a new word today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;highfalutin: pompous or pretentious&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source article with the word: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/china/2016-09/14/content_26797048.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/china/2016-09/14/content_26797048.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2019/07/css-custom-properties-cascade/&quot;&gt;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2019/07/css-custom-properties-cascade/&lt;/a&gt;
Custom properties in CSS.
This is just so damn cool&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;p {
  color: var(--paragraph);
}

#inner {
  --paragraph: green;
}

#outer {
  --paragraph: red;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also specify functions in CSS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fallback variable: var(—stripes-angle, 90deg)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[TIL#5]]></title><description><![CDATA[EMs are relative to their parent’s font size
REMs are relative to a base font-size]]></description><link>https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/17072019/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/17072019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;EMs are relative to their parent’s font size&lt;br /&gt;
REMs are relative to a base font-size&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[TIL#4]]></title><description><![CDATA[https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2019/07/css-custom-properties-cascade/ BEM syntax actually influences the order in which properties are…]]></description><link>https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/16072019/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/16072019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2019/07/css-custom-properties-cascade/&quot;&gt;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2019/07/css-custom-properties-cascade/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BEM syntax actually influences the order in which properties are applied!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[TIL#3]]></title><description><![CDATA[Can have gradient background for texts https://css-tricks.com/snippets/css/gradient-text/]]></description><link>https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/15072019/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/15072019/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Can have gradient background for texts &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/snippets/css/gradient-text/&quot;&gt;https://css-tricks.com/snippets/css/gradient-text/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[TIL#2]]></title><description><![CDATA[For flex direction = column, flex-basis=0 refers to the height, so we need to specify width:0 to make sure the initial width is 0 instead of…]]></description><link>https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/10072019/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/10072019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;For flex direction = column, flex-basis=0 refers to the height, so we need to specify width:0 to make sure the initial width is 0 instead of their initial content&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Joy of Doing Things without the Need for Justification]]></title><description><![CDATA[Recently, i gave a talk at TalkCSS about drawing with pure CSS. It seems the header of one of the slides made a good tagline, and that is…]]></description><link>https://smokinclove.github.io//the-joy-of-doing-things-without-the-need-for-justification/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://smokinclove.github.io//the-joy-of-doing-things-without-the-need-for-justification/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Recently, i gave a talk at TalkCSS about drawing with pure CSS. It seems the header of one of the slides made a good tagline, and that is the title of this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can watch the video &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j7bx3CTkq-E&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, courtesy of Engineers.sg. You can follow them on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@engineersftw&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From young, i have always loved drawing. My first inspirations for going on drawing spree when i was young were manga characters, from series like Sailor Moon to Inuyasha, from Naruto to D Gray Man. I could draw for hours on end. I (and my sister, who is actually my twin) basically led to the formation of a drawing club in my secondary school, because one fine day during a period where students were supposed to register for a club to join and attend their session, i, who obviously did not register for any because i thought i could just walk in (hail the power of youth &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;¯\_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/code&gt;), assumed there would be a drawing club (i only realized there was none months later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spotted a teacher whom i knew to be an art teacher, but not of my class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked up to him and ask: &lt;em&gt;Sir, is there a drawing lesson today?&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He thought for 3 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he said &lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was how my sister and i attended the lesson as the only two participants. We drew trees on our school playground and learnt how to go about shading them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As weeks passed by, more kids joined the lessons. A long time later when we both were too busy preparing for our exams, we quit the club, but i can still remember passing by a growing group of kids, sitting on the school benches, drawing away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now back to topic. We as responsible adults in developed countries such as Singapore are conditioned to act rationally. But i do not think we were all born like that. As toddlers, we did what we want. Kids do not rationalize their actions. It is us adults who teach them to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when i saw &lt;a href=&quot;http://diana-adrianne.com/purecss-francine/&quot; target=&quot;__blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;this Pure CSS Francine by Diana Smith&lt;/a&gt;, i decided. I will draw whatever i want, with CSS. Just because i want to. But first would explore the idea of drawing anime characters because they allow for creative manifestations of the human body parts and of course, because i am a fan of anime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does doing things like this feel right? Maybe not. But to me, i know it does feel one thing. It feels…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liberating&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can call this escaping reality, or going back in time. Be a kid again. Both work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reminds me of a Japanese fairly tail i read about a kid asking the Sun to let him stay a kid forever, to which the Sun replied that we would one day return to being a child again. The boy grows up to be an adult and then an elderly. Eventually getting so old to the point of losing his mental agility, the man behaves just like a kid, looking at the Sun innocently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is my call out to you. If you have not already, consider doing something which you do not have any confirmation about whether it will pay off (as to what pay off means, that is a very objective question &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;¯\_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But try this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:120%&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get on a random train and figure out the correct way later. Give drinks to a homeless person (if you are wondering where to find them, contact Homeless Hearts of Singapore). Talk to a prostitute. Befriend a same sex couple. Go to Dorothy’s bar. Even better, find out if they have any dress code and blend in. Oh, while you are at it, go spend your New Year countdown party there too. Get a haircut in the next foreign country when you are traveling.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might find some of these things making no sense. I know. I did all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And i still do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~Cheerio~&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[TIL#1]]></title><description><![CDATA[Safari does not support transparent in gradients. We need to use a fully transparent color instead with opacity 0. See https://codepen.io…]]></description><link>https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/09072019/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://smokinclove.github.io//learn-a-new-thing-or-two-everyday/09072019/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safari does not support transparent in gradients. We need to use a fully transparent color instead with opacity 0. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/pik_at/pen/dYWLrR&quot;&gt;https://codepen.io/pik_at/pen/dYWLrR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello World! I finally get started on working on my website/blog… Better late than never, right? Hello, I am a female developer based in…]]></description><link>https://smokinclove.github.io//hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://smokinclove.github.io//hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; get started on working on my website/blog…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better late than never, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, I am a female developer based in Singapore. I mainly work on front end, and currently explore CSS as a tool for drawing.
Here are my social media links:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SmokinClove&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; - my handle is derived from the Smoking Clover - a computer visual hack by Bill Gosper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/SmokinClove/&quot;&gt;Codepen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bokukage&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; - my Twitter handle is an outlier from the rest, it is derived from a quote from Kuroko Tetsuya (Kuroko no Basuke): &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;ボクは、影だ&lt;/code&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://crimsoncoffeeblack.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Personal (not really) Diary&lt;/a&gt; - i do actually have an existing blog where i write whatever i feel, my interactions with people, and sometimes, my goals. I usually consider it an online diary rather than a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/ValkEerie&quot;&gt;Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt; - i actually was actively making music as a hobby for a few years, and beside this account i also made &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/veintage&quot;&gt;another one&lt;/a&gt; for lyrical songs. Although i have faced a songwriter’s block for about 2-3 years now, i do hope to get back to developing music with my newfound programming knowledge. Oh, and if you are interested in helping to sing the lyrics for my songs please contact me ヽ(ﾟ∀ﾟ )ﾉ Pity this poor woman having to belt out her songs like a duck.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>